# Joey Gryder

# **Sr. Software Engineer** in Test

Technical Lead - QA Team

# Joey Gryder

Mt. Pleasant. SC

joey.gryder@gmail.com https://www.joeygryder.com

## Skills

While comfortable in many programming languages and paradigms, my primary focus has been on object-oriented languages when building RESTful web-services / back-end services, with several years experience each in VB / C# .NET and Ruby.

I have additional experience in React, along with SQL Server / MySQL for relational storage, and more recently DynamoDB for NoSQL persistence. I'm also well versed in various AWS cloud service offerings, with a recent interest in Serverless technologies.

# **Experience**

**BoomTown ROI / Sr. Software Engineer in Test - Technical Lead**AUGUST 2014 - PRESENT, CHARLESTON, SC

Responsible for the architecture and implementation of the first test automation framework at BoomTown, built with Cucumber, React, Sinatra, Docker, and AWS.

Helped grow the QA engineering team from two initial SETs to a staff of over ten engineers, through internal training and promotions of QA Analysts, as well as external hiring of new engineering graduates.

# Blackbaud / Sr. Software Quality Engineer

JUNE 2011 - AUGUST 2014, CHARLESTON, SC

Contributed to an internally maintained WPF / VB.NET application used by manual testers to interface with SOAP-based web services.

Built a Bootstrap / jQuery / MVC.NET testing dashboard to allow for the execution and storage of test automation results.

Load-tested various back-end services responsible for Blackbaud's payment processing and e-mail systems.

#### **Education**

### **Appalachian State University** / B.S. in Computer Science

JANUARY 2009 - MAY 2011, BOONE, NC Summa Cum Laude

#### **UNC Asheville / B.A.** in Political Science

AUGUST 2003 - MAY 2007, ASHEVILLE, NC